Confederate States of America Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Confederate Constitutional Documents, 1861-1883 (Box 74-76, Reel 36-38)
  - Confederate constitution, facsimile, printed in New York, 1883 (Box 74, Reel 36 *)
  - Fragments and drafts of constitution, 1861 (Box 75, Reel 37 *)
  - Printed copies of the constitution with amendments, 1861
  - Amended constitution with holograph corrections, 1861
  - Copies of the provisional and permanent constitution, 1861
  - Ordinances of secession and related papers from individual Confederate states, 1861
  - Constitutions and other documents of the Confederate States, printed, 1861 (Box 76, Reel 38 *)
- Department of Justice, 1860-1867 (Box 77-81, Reel 38 *)
  Court costs, minute books, docket books, garnishment petitions, rules, and related material for the Confederate States of America and the United States and District courts in Alabama, Louisiana, and Mississippi.
  - Court costs, 1863-1867 (Box 77, Reel 38 *)
  - Confederate States District Court of Alabama, 1863
  - United States District Court of Alabama, 1865-1867
  - Confederate States Court for the Northern District of Alabama, 1863 (Box 78, Reel 38 *)
  - Confederate States District Court of the Northern Division of Mississippi, records and minute book, 1861-1865 (Box 79, Reel 38 *)
  - Trial docket (Box 80, Reel 38 *)
  - Confederate States District Court of Alabama, 1861-1863
  - United States District Court of Alabama, 1860
  - Records of the Confederate States District Court of Louisiana, 1861-1862 (Box 81, Reel 38 *)
  - Garnishment petitions and rules, 1861-1862
- Department of the Treasury, 1860-1865 (Box 82-93, Reel 39-49)
  Correspondence to and from various officials of the Treasury Department, estimates of funds needed, a letterbook, circulars of the United States Treasury Department, and related material.
  - Correspondence, 1860-1864 (Box 82, Reel 39 *)
    - To A. J. Guirot, 1860-1864
    - To Bolling Baker, 1861-1862 (Box 83, Reel 40 *)
    - To Bolling Baker, 1861-1862 (Box 83, Reel 41 *)
    - To Lewis Conger, 1861-1862 (Box 83, Reel 41 *)
    - From F. H. Hatch (Box 84, Reel 42 *)
      - 1861-1862
      - 1861-1862 (Box 85, Reel 42 *)
      - 1861-1862 (Box 86, Reel 43 *)
    - To F. H. Hatch, 1861 (Box 87, Reel 44 *)
      - Baker, Bolling
      - Cabinet members
      - Clitherall, Alexander B.
      - Cruger, Lewis
      - Elmore, E. C.
      - Light House Bureau
      - Memminger, C. G.
      - Miscellany, (1 folder)
      - Miscellany, (10 folders) (Box 88, Reel 45 *)
    - To John Boston
      - 1861
      - 1861-1862 (Box 89, Reel 46 *)
      - 1862-1864 (Box 89, Reel 47 *)
  - Collectors' estimates of funds needed for customhouses and lighthouses, 1861 (Box 90, Reel 48 *)
  - Register's Office, letterbook, 1863-1864 (Box 91, Reel 49 *)
    - Jones, C. F.
    - Tyler, Robert
  - United States Treasury Department, circulars, 1861-1863 (Box 92, Reel 49 *)
  - Miscellany, 1861-1865 (Box 93, Reel 49 *)
    - Correspondence
      - Clark, M. H.
      - Hunter, R. M. T.
      - Memminger, C. G.
      - Tyler, Robert
    - Government expenditure list
    - An impression of the seal of the Treasury
    - Reports of the secretary
    - Tax and bond receipts
- Post Office Department, 1861-1865 (Box 94-108, Reel 49-62)
  Appointment Bureau letterbooks, lists, account books, contracts and schedules, a report of the postmaster general, and related material.
  - Appointment Bureau letterbooks (Box 94, Reel 49 *)
    - 1861-1862
    - 1862-1863 (Box 95, Reel 50 *)
    - 1863 (Box 96, Reel 51 *)
    - 1863-1865 (Box 97, Reel 51 *)
  - Official letterbooks (Box 98, Reel 52 *)
    - 1861-1862
    - 1861-1863 (Box 99, Reel 52 *)
  - Appointment Bureau lists: Alabama, Arkansas, and Texas, 1861-1864, (1 vol.) (Box 100, Reel 53 *, Box 101)
  - Register of current accounts in post office in Arkansas, Florida, Tennessee, and Texas, 1862 (Box 102, Reel 53 *)
  - Contracts and schedules, 1861-1863 (Box 103, Reel 54 *)
    - Mississippi
      - Nos. 601-7671
      - Nos. 7405-7488 (Box 104, Reel 55 *)
      - Nos. 7490-7579 (Box 105, Reel 56 *)
      - Nos. 7580-7599 (Box 106, Reel 57 *)
    - Virginia
      - Nos. 4170-4170 (Box 106, Reel 57 *)
      - Nos. 4171-4199 (Box 106, Reel 58 *)
      - Nos. 4201-4237 (Box 107, Reel 59 *)
      - Nos. 4237-4247 (Box 107, Reel 60 *)
      - Nos. 4300-4310 (Box 108, Reel 61 *)
      - Nos. 291, 4188, 4311-4319 (Box 108, Reel 62 *)
  - Report of the postmaster general, 1861-1862 (Box 108, Reel 62 *)
- War Department, 1861-1865 (Box 109-118, Reel 63-68)
  Correspondence, reports, orders, circulars, a letterbook, regimental records, quartermaster records, general orders, captured Union dispatches, field returns, certificates, lists, and related material.
  - Official correspondence, L. P. Walker, 1861 (Box 109, Reel 63 *)
  - List of official communications, 1864-1865 (Box 110, Reel 63 *)
  - Miscellany, 1861-1865 (Box 111, Reel 64 *)
    - Correspondence
    - Letterbooks
      - Bee, Hamilton P.
      - Lopez, Albino
    - Report of the secretary
    - Transcripts from the papers of Jubal A. Early
  - Circulars and regulations (Box 112, Reel 64 *)
  - General Orders
    - Headquarters
      - Confederate States of America, Army
      - Army of Northern Virginia
      - Department of Northern Virginia
      - Army of the Potomac
      - Department of Virginia and North Carolina
      - Army of Tennessee
      - Department of the Trans-Mississippi
      - Miscellany
      - District of Arkansas, James Elliott
      - Alabama Brigade
      - Captured federal dispatches
  - Regimental papers, muster and pay rolls, 1861-1865, undated (Box 113, Reel 65 *)
    - Arkansas
    - Georgia
    - Louisiana
    - Mississippi
    - Virginia, (9 folders); (25 folders) (Box 114, Reel 65 *)
    - Mississippi (Box 115, Reel 66 *)
  - Record book, 1863-1865
  - Quartermaster records, 1863-1864 (Box 116, Reel 66 *)
    - Articles sold, lost, or destroyed
    - Disbursements
    - Receipts
    - Requisitions for forage
    - Reports of articles purchased
    - Reports of articles received from officers
    - Special requisitions
    - Quarterly returns, Lake, M.
    - Miscellany (Box 117, Reel 67 *)
      - Barbour, A. M.
      - Lake, M.
      - Mallory, C. R.
      - Thompson, George G.
    - Railroad tickets
    - Tax Receipts
    - Certificates (Box 118, Reel 68 *)
      - Furlough
      - Discharge
      - Death
    - Discharge book
    - Field returns
    - Oaths of officers
    - Officer reports
    - Ordnance reports
    - Requisition lists
    - Safe conduct passes
    - Wounded lists
- Navy Department, 1861-1865 (Box 119-120, Reel 69-70)
  Accounts, circulars, correspondence, reports, logbooks, certificates, and related material.
  - Accounts (Box 119, Reel 69 *)
    - Fort Sumter, 1863
    - Fort Tennesse, 1863
    - Missouri, 1863
  - Circulars, 1861
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and records, 1861-1864
  - Discharge certificates, 1864
  - Pay and receipt rates, 1861
  - Transcribed statements, 1884
  - Correspondence, Raphael Semmes, 1862 (Box 120, Reel 69 *)
  - Reports, 1862
  - Register, 1862
  - Logs of vessels in Bermuda and Nassau, 1861-1865
- Miscellany, 1858-1872 (Box 121-123, Reel 70)
  Memoranda, letters, bills, lists, receipts, published material, and printed forms relating to the provenance and description of the collection, several states (Georgia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and Virginia) within the Confederacy, and other facets of the history of the Confederate States of America.
  - Lists of the records (Box 121, Reel 70 *)
  - Report of Thomas O. Selfridge on the purchase of the Pickett Papers, 1872
  - South Carolina, ordnance correspondence, 1860-1861
  - North Carolina, executive correspondence, 1859-1864
  - Georgia, executive correspondence, 1861-1864
  - Tennessee, executive correspondence, 1858-1861
  - Virginia, executive correspondence, 1861
  - Table of distances, undated
  - Seal of the Confederacy
  - Crop subscriptions, 1861
  - Inaugural program, undated
  - Alabama's ordnance of secession, 1861
  - List of the officers of the Confederacy, undated
  - Published statutes, orders, proclamations (Box 122)
  - Blank forms See also Oversize (Box 123)
- Additions, 1854-1889 (Box 124)
  Autographs, correspondence, register of surgeons, financial bonds, and other material.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein. The register of surgeons is available only on microfilm (one reel). Shelf no. 10,164.
  - Autographs, 1886-1889, undated (Box 124)
  - Bonds, 1854-1864, undated See Oversize, (3 folders)
  - Miscellany, 1862-1865, undated
  - Register of surgeons, Army of Tennessee, 1861-1865, Available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 10,164
- Oversize, 1854-1864 (Box OV 1-OV 5)
  Blank forms and financial bonds.
  Arranged and described according to the series, folders, and containers from which the items were removed.
  - Miscellany (Box OV 1)
    - Blank forms (Container 123)
  - Additions (Box OV 2)
    - Bonds (Container 124)
      - 1854, 1859-1862
      - 1862-1863 (Box OV 3)
      - 1863 (Box OV 4)
      - 1864 (Box OV 5)